bigmarker.com 2018-12-30

# BigMarker Legal Docs

  *  Terms of Service 
  *  Privacy Policy 
  *  Copyright Policy 

BigMarker.com, LLC, located in Chicago, Illinois USA, and its affiliates (“BigMarker”), are on a mission to connect billions of people with knowledge, passion, and experience. To achieve this mission, BigMarker provides a webinar platform that enables creators to share their knowledge and grow their audience, and consumers to join in from around the world.

BigMarker’s platform is comprised of products including websites, mobile applications, APIs, and other tools, resources, and information provided as part of the BigMarker services (our “Services”).

This Privacy Policy governs our data collection, processing and usage practices. We update this Privacy Policy periodically. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by sending you an email notification.

1\. Use of BigMarker’s Services 

By becoming a user of BigMarker’s Services, you voluntarily and willfully provide BigMarker with certain information, including personally identifiable information, which BigMarker collects to provide the Services.

You may become a BigMarker user by becoming a Customer, when you start a free trial or paid subscription to host webinars (the “Subscription Service”). You may also become a BigMarker user by subscribing to a channel or registering for, attending, or viewing a webinar created by a BigMarker Customer.

If you have any hesitations or concerns about providing information to BigMarker, having your information displayed on the BigMarker website or otherwise used in a manner consistent with our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service, then you should not become a user of BigMarker’s Services and, if you are already a user, you should close your account. Our Support team is available to help you; you can reach them at support@bigmarker.com.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our treatment of the information you provide us, please write to us by email at privacy@bigmarker.com or by mail to BigMarker, LLC 223 West Erie Street, Chicago, IL 60654, USA, Attn: Privacy.

2\. Information We Collect 

When You Visit Our Websites 

You are free to visit our Websites without providing any Personal Information. When you register for a webinar or for the Subscription Service, we request that you provide Personal Information about yourself, and we collect Navigational Information. 

When You Use Our Mobile Applications 

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Apps on your mobile device. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. In addition to information we collect on our Websites, when you use our Mobile Apps we may also collect your city location, device model and version, device identifier (or “UDID”), OS version, and your BigMarker Subscription Service credentials.

We may send push notifications from time to time in order to update you about events or promotions. If you no longer wish to receive such communications, you may turn them off in your device’s Settings.

We may link information we store within the analytics software to Personal Information you submit within the Mobile App. We do this to improve services we offer you and improve our marketing, analytics and site functionality.

"Personal Information" 

Personal Information refers to any information you voluntarily submit to us and that identifies you personally, including contact information such as your name, e-mail address, company name, address, phone number, and other information about yourself or your business. Personal Information can also include information about any transactions, both free and paid, that you enter into on the Websites, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.

Personal Information also includes Navigational Information or Payment Information where such information can directly or indirectly identify an individual. Navigational information refers to information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and pages viewed. Please see the "Navigation Information" section below. Payment information includes information we collect and process from you when you subscribe to the Subscription Service, including credit cards numbers and billing information, using third party PCI-compliant service providers. Except for this, we do not collect Sensitive Information from you.

You have the option to provide certain Personal Data to BigMarker. This optional Personal Data may be required in order to receive specific services. By providing such information, you are agreeing that BigMarker may store, process, and review such information. BigMarker may use this information for the purpose for which it was collected, and this information may be stored for as long as is necessary to provide you with our services.

Information You Post Onto BigMarker Websites, Channels, and Webinars 

Please note that information that you voluntarily make Public in your user profile, or which you disclose in a Public Channel will become publicly available and viewable by others. It is up to BigMarker users to be aware of what information they are releasing to the public. BigMarker accepts no responsibility or liability for any private information that was inadvertently made public. If any information has been made public that was not intended to be made public, please send an email to report@bigmarker.com.

Ways Users Share Information With BigMarker 

**Registration information:** When you register for a webinar, you create a BigMarker account so that you can come back later to log in to attend and view the webinar(s) you registered for, and retain access to past webinars, purchased webinars, etc. The personal information you share when registering for a webinar is also shared with the creator of that webinar. By registering for a webinar, you are opting into sharing the information you provide on the registration form with the webinar host, and giving them permission to use that information to contact you for updates and marketing purposes.

**Creating a BigMarker account:** You may also create a BigMarker account from the BigMarker homepage or website, mobile applications, or when signing up for the Subscription Service. To sign up for an account, you are required to provide your name, email address and a password.

**Information you choose to share in your profile:** You can choose to share or not share information such as your picture, bio, passions and interests, expertise, education and certifications.

**Information you choose to share within a channel or webinar room:** You can choose to share or not share posts to a channel, upload documents or presentations, upload webcam video feeds in a webinar, upload audio feeds in a webinar, and post comments, chat messages, Q&A questions, polls, etc.

**Information others share about you:** We receive information about you from other users, such as comments on a file that you uploaded, or in the case of guest presenters, profile data that is provided about you by a webinar host who has invited you to guest present. We may also receive information about you from other users’ communications with you or within a channel. Users can self-police their use of our Services by reporting any suspected foul play. If you would like to report suspected foul play or request information be removed from the BigMarker website, then you should contact BigMarker at report@bigmarker.com.

**Banking and Payment information:** We may ask you to provide banking and payment information to allow you to pay for the Subscription Service, pay for Add-ons, pay subscription fees to a channel, and participate in, sponsor, or host a webinar. In order to fulfill your requests for paid services, we share your banking and payment information with payment processors. For more information on this topic, please see the section about how we share your information with partners, below.

**Correspondence between you and BigMarker:** We can correspond with you using email, chat and text messages, notices on the BigMarker website and other communication methods.

**Electronic identification data:** When you view and interact with our Services, we also collect your IP addresses, your operating system type, your web browser type, URLs of websites in which you arrive or leave the BigMarker website, and other similar information.

**Cookies:** Cookies allow us to recognize you, customize your experience, and provide advertisements.

**Mobile Applications:** When you view and interact with our Services, we also collect your IP addresses, your operating system type, your web browser type, URLs of websites in which you arrive or leave the BigMarker website, your mobile carrier or service provider, your Internet service provider (“ISP”), and other similar information.

**Third-party services:** We will receive your prior consent before you interact with third-party services available through our Services such as surveys and questionnaires.

3\. Our Use Of Your Information 

We use the information we collect only in compliance with this Privacy Policy. Customers who subscribe to our Subscription Services are obligated through our agreements with them to comply with this Privacy Policy. 

We Never Sell Personal Information 

We will never sell your Personal Information to any third party. 

We use the information you provide to: 

  * Provide you with Services;
  * Take, process and deliver your payment orders made via our Services;
  * Provide you with customer support and help with troubleshooting problems;
  * Develop and improve our Services;
  * Implement and support our marketing, promotions and public relations;
  * Perform and support our internal operations such as troubleshooting, data collection and analysis, testing, verification, research, development and service improvements; 
  * Enable you to share information and communicate with other users and channels;
  * Develop and improve the services offered by third parties;
  * Determine your geographical location;
  * Send you service or promotional information via email, text messages, and notices on the BigMarker website; 
  * Administer your user or channel account;
  * Resolve your reported disputes and suspected foul play;
  * Recommend other users to connect with you.

Sharing Your Information With Webinar Hosts

When you register for, purchase tickets to, or donate to a webinar, channel, or related services on the BigMarker, you consent to providing your Personal Data to the Organizers, Hosts and Presenters of such webinar and related page, if applicable. These Organizers are not bound to treat your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy. You agree that we are not responsible for the actions of these Organizers with respect to your Personal Data. It is important that you review the applicable policies of the Organizers of a webinar before providing Personal Data or other information in connection with that webinar. 

Legal basis for processing Personal Information (EEA visitors only)

If you are a Customer located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), then you are the Data Controller of Customer Data, and BigMarker (BigMarker, LLC of Chicago, Illinois, USA) shall process Customer Data only as a Data Processor acting on behalf of Customer.

Our Data Processing Agreement with our customers provides more detail into the scope and roles around processing customer data. BigMarker's Data Protection Officer can be contacted at support@bigmarker.com.

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information). Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

4\. How We Share Information We Collect 

Legal Requirements & Government

BigMarker may disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, to protect BigMarker’s interests, fight against fraud and to enforce our policies or to protect anyone’s rights, property, or safety. 

Suppliers, Vendors, and Sub-processors 

BigMarker partners with companies like Amazon, Google, and Microsoft to provide the infrastructure required for people to access BigMarker Services around the world. The Sub-processors currently engaged by BigMarker are included in our Data Processor Agreement. BigMarker shares information with these companies in order to to provide its Services. 

Service Providers 

We may employ other companies and people to provide services to customers and users and may need to share your information with them to provide information, products or services to you. Examples may include providing marketing assistance (e.g., helping your promote your webinars, editing your videos), analyzing data, processing credit card payments, supplementing the information you provide us in order to provide you with better service, and providing customer service or support. In all cases where we share your information with such agents, we explicitly require the agent to acknowledge and adhere to our privacy and customer data handling policies. 

BigMarker Partners 

In order to provide its services, BigMarker may share with its business partners, in a secure environment, your personal and traffic data. These business partners may include group companies, carriers, partner service providers and/or agents. They are required to take measures to protect your personal and traffic data in accordance with the law.

BigMarker products and services may be licensed or co-branded and offered together with or directly by a partner company. If you register for or use such products, you consent to both BigMarker’s and the partner company’s use of personal data collected in connection with the licensed or co-branded product. BigMarker, BigMarker’s local partner, or the operator or company facilitating your communication may provide personal data, communications content and/or traffic data to an appropriate judicial, law enforcement or government authority lawfully requesting such information. BigMarker will provide all reasonable assistance and information to fulfill this request and you hereby consent to such disclosure.

Corporate Events

If we (or our assets) are acquired by another company, whether by merger, acquisition, bankruptcy or otherwise, that company would receive all information gathered by BigMarker on the Websites and the Subscription Service. In this event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your Personal Information, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

5\. International Transfer of Information 

We partner with Amazon and Microsoft to provide access to our Services. Accordingly, your information may be stored and processed in any country in which Amazon, Microsoft, or any of their affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. BigMarker reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using BigMarker software, products or websites, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. 

6\. Your Information Choices for Your Accounts & Channels 

Public Channels: 

If you subscribe to a public channel, your name will automatically be made public. Further, any information you choose to share within your profile and within a public channel will be made public.

When you create a BigMarker account, you will automatically be entered into the BigMarker Channel. The BigMarker Channel is public, so your name, as well as any information you choose to share within your profile will be made public. If you do not want your name or profile information made public, you can leave the BigMarker Channel. This can be done by navigating to the BigMarker Channel page at bigmarker.com/BMchannel, scrolling over the “My Profile” button and clicking on the “Leave Channel” link.

Private Channels:

Information you share within a private channel will only be made available to other users of such private channel.

If you only belong to a private channel, then your name and profile information will only be made available to the users of those channels. However, if you also belong to a public channel, your name and profile information will be made public.

You may also be given a chance to provide additional profile information that is unique to a specific channel. For a private channel, any information you choose to share will only be available to other users of such private channel. For a public channel, any information you choose to share will be made public.

In order to improve your user experience, we use analytics partners including Google Analytics and Mouseflow to gather statistical and analytical information about how you use our Services.

8\. Advertising & Promotion and Opt Out 

From time-to-time, you may receive promotional materials from BigMarker announcing special offers and featured BigMarker webinars or channels. 

BigMarker and its promotional partners may use non-personally identifiable information that you have provided in your profile or otherwise provided to BigMarker, such as your age, gender, language, country of residence, time zone, as well as information about your relationship with our Services in order to provide offers and promotional materials likely to be of greater interest to you and to help BigMarker measure and improve the performance of our promotional campaigns.

You may opt out of promotional communications at any time by clicking the ‘Opt Out’ link at the bottom of emails, or managing your communications settings in your personal profile.

9\. Linked websites and third party applications 

The BigMarker website and its web pages may contain links that allow you to leave the BigMarker website and access other websites. Such hyperlinked websites are not under the control of BigMarker and may have different privacy policies. The BigMarker Privacy Policy applies only to your personal information that is acquired on the BigMarker website and its web pages or through your use of our Services. BigMarker urges you to be careful when providing any personal information online and BigMarker accepts no responsibility or liability for these other websites. 

From time-to-time, we may ask you to provide information about your BigMarker experience, which we may use to improve our Services. You are at no time under any obligation to provide any such information.

We reserve the right to use email, text messages and other communication methods to notify you of any claims related to your use of our Services, including without limitation claims of violation of any third party rights.

BigMarker is not intended for or designed to attract users under the age of 13, and we do not intentionally or knowingly collect personal information on our websites from anyone under the age of 13. We encourage parents to be involved in their children’s online activities to ensure that no information is collected from a child without parental permission. 

Our Privacy Policy is effective as of June 2012 and last updated as of May 2018. We reserve the right to amend our Privacy Policy at any time. Your continued use of BigMarker following changes to our terms constitute acceptance of our amended terms. 

User data (including personal data, financial information, and uploaded content) is stored safely and securely in the cloud using industry-standard encryption and data protection practices. We never make this information available to anyone. As users of web and cloud services ourselves, we take security very seriously. 

Thank you for being a part of the BigMarker movement! Please do not hesitate to reach out to us at any time if you have questions, concerns, feedback, or other requests. You can use the following email addresses to reach us, and we will generally respond within a day or two.

  * For information: info@bigmarker.com
  * For support: support@bigmarker.com
  * For feedback: feedback@bigmarker.com
  * To report misuse: report@bigmarker.com
